So in this lecture, we're going to discuss how inference parameters influence foundation model behavior.
But what are inference parameters?
So earlier when we had discussed how does Amazon bedrock work?
We said user input is who is the best tennis player?
And then we said we're going to make this API request to bedrock with some configuration parameters where we identified the model ID.
So this is the model ID to which the request should be sent to then we sent the prompt, which is the user input.
And then along with that, we also sent some configuration parameters.
So we said, okay, max token is going to 512, temperature is going to be 0.5.
So these configuration parameters that you sent along with the prompt are called as inference parameters.
So there are broadly two kind of inference parameters and you might see some variation in a few models, but generally speaking, these are the two main ones.
So the first one is randomness and diversity and this controls the creativity of the response that you're going to get from the foundation model and we'll get to what we mean by creativity of the response in a little bit.
But from the randomness and diversity control perspective, there are three key attributes that you can control temperature, top key, and top key.
Then the second one is the length.
So the length of the output that is generated by the foundation model based on your prompt.
So there are two ways in which you can control the length of the response, one is max tokens and seconds the stop sequence.
Okay, now let's try and understand this in more detail through an example.
So the first inference parameter is randomness and diversity.
So let's say the prompt we're going to send to the foundation model is I hear the hoof beats of and our foundation model is going to complete this sentence.
So we know that foundation models generate one word at a time to complete the sentence.
Now to complete the next word in this sentence foundation model may come up with hundreds of words that can come after off here.
In our case, let's just assume that it comes up with five words.
So first it comes up with horse and it gives it a probability score of 0.4.
Then it says win and it gives a probability score of 0.2.
Maybe unicorns with 0.1 probability score and change in distance, which is 0.05.
Okay, now let's see through temperature, top can, top P, how we can control what is the next word that would be generated.
So for temperature, different foundation models would have a different range.
Maybe some will have 0 to 5, some may have 0 to 1.
So for our use case, let's just assume the values between 0 to 1.
Okay, now if you have a low value, which is closer to 0, then model tends to select higher probability words.
And if you see in this scenario, then the word with highest probability is horse 0.4.
So it's going to come up with this word horse.
That means it's a highly predictable response.
So now if you want to be really creative, then the temperature value we can have for our foundation model is let's say one or closer to one.
And when we provide a higher value, temperature further away from 0, the model may select a lower probability word.
And in our case, the word with lowest probability was change in distance.
So the next word, it's going to come up with this change in distance.
So next we have top K and it can have value between 1 to 500 and it may vary from model to model.
So what does top K do?
The cut off where the model no longer selects the words.
So let's say in our case, obviously we have only five words here, but let's say if we put K is equal to 50, the model selects from 50 of the most probable words.
So now in our example, let's say if we put the value of K equal to three, so it's only going to select the top three words, horse, wind and unicorn.
And now let's say our temperature value was equal to one.
Now, since only these three words are selected, so the word we have here would be unicorn and not change in distance.
So that's how you can use a combination of temperature and top K to determine the response from the foundation model.
Then we have top P and these values can vary from model to model.
So but what does top K do?
It caps choices based on the sum of the probabilities.
So let's say in our example, you have the top P value as 0.6.
So what it will do is it will add the probability of first two words.
So we have horse and wind.
So it's going to only select these two words.
And let's say if you have low value of temperature, then it's going to select again, horse, so should not change much.
But let's say if you select a higher value, then it's going to select this word, wind and not change in distance.
So that's how you can use a combination of temperature, top K and top P to determine the creative response from the model.
Now, let's go and understand the second inference parameter, which is length.
Now, let's see, we provide a prompt to the foundation model where we see right an essay on horse.
So how does the foundation model know?
How many words to generate if we have not provided any guidance in the prompt?
So that's where the inference parameter length comes into click.
So it controls the length of the generated response.
So not only does it keep the response concise, but it also helps control cost.
Just remember the more the number of words, the more the number of output tokens, more is going to be the cost.
Now the length in the parameter can be controlled by max length and stop sequence.
So max length specify is the maximum number of tokens to use in the generated response.
So now remember, it's the max number of tokens.
It can also generate lesser number of words or tokens, but once you provide the max length, it cannot go beyond that.
And that can vary between one to 64,000 and it varies from model to model.
And 64,000 is maximum, which is in the case of entropic claw model.
So if you see our example previously, where we had sent the API request to them is in bedrock.
Here we had this max underscore token attribute and we had said 512 tokens and
512 tokens approximately 375 words or so.
So which means once it generates an essay on horse, it cannot be more than 375 words.
It can be less, but not more than that.
Now the second one is stop secans.
So now it's clear to us that it cannot generate more than whatever token limit that we have provided.
But how does it know when to stop and there are three ways in which it can be done.
So the first one is model decided stop.
So based on the model training, it automatically determines what could be the appropriate length for a essay like this.
So that's the first one, the second one is system and force, which is when you are sending the inference parameters to the model.
And here you can see max tokens.
So if you provide the max token length, then we already discussed it's not going to exceed that.
So the third one is stop secans.
So in stop secans, you can provide some keywords.
So you provide this closed curly bracket or you provide a tag answer, as you can see in this case.
So what's the relevance this now let's take an example.
Let's say now let's say you have built an insurance generator application where you get the claim form you extract the data from the claim form.
Then you do some formatting of that extracted data and then you persist in the backend system.
Maybe RDS, DynamoDB and so on.
Now let's say our DynamoDB accepts the data in this format as a JSON object where we have the first name John and last name as do.
So what will happen is when we have the stop secans in the format of curly brackets, then it does a match and when he sees in the response closed curly bracket.
It will stop generating any further tokens post that and how is that useful.
So if it generates any more tokens post that curly bracket, then it will not match to the backend schema.
So that is one of the scenarios in which you can use stop secans.
Okay, so that's pretty much it from this lecture as in the next lecture.